https://www.monoprice.com/privacy

If you are visually impaired and are having difficulty navigating this site, please call our Customer Support line via our toll free number 1 (877) 271-2592.
Never Miss a Deal.
Be the first to know about our latest deals, product launches, and exclusive promotions.
SIGN UP FOR EMAIL DEALS`
Email Address
SHOP WITH CONFIDENCE
Lifetime warranty on all cables and TV wall mounts, one year warranty on most other items
30 day money back guarantee
Easy return
100% safe SSL encrypted shopping
PCI-DSS Level 1 Compliant
PRIVACY POLICY
Our Commitment to Accessibility
If you are visually impaired and need assistance accessing our Privacy Policy, please call our Customer Support line via our toll free number 1 (877) 271-2592 for assistance.
This privacy statement covers the site https://www.monoprice.com and Stitch by Monoprice mobile application. This is the privacy policy for all websites and mobile applications operated by Monoprice, Inc. (DBA Monoprice.com). This Privacy Statement describes how Monoprice, Inc. collects and uses the personal information you provide. It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your personal information. Because this website wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider.
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.
By displaying the trustmark, Monoprice.com has agreed to inform you on:
What personally identifiable information of yours Monoprice.com collects
The organization collecting the information
How the information is used
With whom the information may be shared
What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information
The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under Monoprice.com control
How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information
Contact Information
Monoprice, Inc.
Attn: Privacy Policy
11701 6th Street
Rancho Cucamonga, CA 91730
USA
You can e-mail us at
privacy@monoprice.com
or reach us by telephone at 877-271-2592.
Privacy Policy Statement
Information Collection and Use
At Monoprice.com, we value our customers and their privacy. We collect, store, use, and share customer information in accordance with this policy. We may store information you enter on our website, including your account information. We use your personal information to ensure efficient processing of your order, to communicate with you, and to improve our website, services, and products. We sometimes send offers to select groups of Monoprice customers on behalf of other businesses. When we do this, we may help our partners verify the effectiveness of their offers to our customers. We will not sell or share identifiable personal information to any third party, except in accordance with this privacy policy or unless we are required to do so by law.
Order
Most of the information collected in the order process will be used to process orders. During the order process, you will have to provide financial information such as your credit card number, expiration date, money order, wire transfer or check information. This information is used for billing purposes and to fulfill your order. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this contact information to get in touch with you. To properly process your credit card information, we must share your personal and financial information with the merchant bank for authorization and approval. This process is protected by an enhanced security system. See the Security section below for more details on security measures and procedures. We do not share your personal and financial information with any third parties, except those specified in the Sharing section of this policy.
We obtain address information about you from third party sources, such as the US Postal Service, UPS, FedEx, Experian, TaxJar, Avalara, No Fraud, to verify your address so we can properly ship your order to you and to prevent fraud.
Invite A Friend
If you feel that the services of monoprice.com would be useful for a third party you know (e.g. your friends or family members etc), you may use our referral service. If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Monoprice.com stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at privacy@monoprice.com
to request that we remove this information from our database.
Registration
Monoprice.com doesn't have a separate registration form to fill out, however you will be registered automatically when placing your first order with us. In order to process your orders placed on this website, you must first complete the contact information form. During the ordering process you will be required to provide your contact information, which includes your name, e-mail address, telephone number and street address. This information is used to provide you with important Monoprice.com services such as automated order status updates via e-mail.
Newsletter
If you wish to subscribe our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe.
Tracking Technologies
Technologies such as: cookies, or similar technologies are used by Monoprice, Inc. and our partners Google, Yahoo, Bing, Oracle, Criteo, affiliates, or analytics or service providers Google and Microsoft. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.
We use cookies for our shopping cart, to remember users cart id and coupons applied. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.
Log Files
As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.
We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.
Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting
We partner with third parties to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may elect to turn off cookies or use your browser’s privacy settings to mask your identity, or you may opt-out by the following consumer choice mechanisms.
Please visit:
Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA)’s self-regulatory opt-out page (http://optout.aboutads.info/) and mobile application based "AppChoices" download page (https://youradchoices.com/appchoices)
European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance (EDAA)'s consumer opt-out page
(http://youronlinechoices.eu)
Network Advertising Initiative (NAI)’s self-regulatory opt-out page
(http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).
Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.
Sharing
We may employ third party companies to perform various functions on our behalf. These functions may include order fulfillment, package delivery, marketing assistance, postal and e-mail delivery, customer service, data analysis, and credit processing. The third parties we contract for these purposes have limited access to your personal information and may not use it for other purposes. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.
In certain situations, Monoprice, Inc. may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities. We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.
If Monoprice, Inc. is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.
Mobile Applications
We may employ 3rd Party OEM solutions to provide technologies for our automation products. Monoprice & its partners agree to protect the personal data for our consumers as defined by legislations related to data protection.
These applications may require new log in credentials to be created and will collect some personal information such as email address, password, geo-location information and photos uploaded by users.
The application gives you the opportunity to de-activate accounts and user data from accounts may be deleted permanently.
Product Reviews
The product reviews section of the Monoprice.com website is for the purpose of our users to share their experiences with our products. The product reviews' section is moderated to ensure accurate and positive testimonials. Published testimonials are genuine and are not edited or altered by Monoprice.com. Monoprice.com reserves the right to post or remove any testimonial at its discretion. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at privacy@monoprice.com.
Blog
Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at privacy@monoprice.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.
Children
Monoprice.com does not sell products to persons under the age of 18. If you are under the age of 18, you are required seek the approval of your parent or guardian to purchase products from this site.
Links
This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Monoprice.com is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this website, Monoprice.com.
Social Media Widgets
Our Website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
Security
We employ the latest 128-bit encryption technology in all areas of the site, which requires you to provide your personal or account information, including online ordering, and order status. Your name, your personal information and especially your credit card number are safely stored in our proprietary systems behind our firewall. Once you type your personal information, it is sent instantly, encrypted, directly to our order processing system which is on a server separate from our internet server. To make sure you have the latest security features on your browser, you may want to download the most recent version of your favorite browser, which should have full Secure Socket Layer (SSL) support.
No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at privacy@monoprice.com.
Special Offers
Our special offers are sent only to customers who grant Monoprice.com permission to send them such information.
To honor the privacy of our users, we offer the option to not receive these types of communications. At the time of your order, you may opt-out of receiving special offers and news by clicking the appropriate field. Furthermore, all special offers are sent via e-mail and include an opt-out link if you no longer wish to receive special offers and news. Customers might still receive intermittent updates on products, services, specials or Monoprice.com news. Please reference the Choice/Opt-out section below for further details on how to be removed from our mailing list should you choose to be removed.
Correction/Updating/Reviewing Personal Information
Monoprice, Inc. acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, customers may change or review and delete/remove their stored account information such as street address or e-mail address through our website by visiting our "My Account" section. You must have your username and password in order to access your account. In the event you forget both your username and password, please contact our customer service department for assistance. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Choice/Opt-out
Our Web site gives you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving marketing communications from us. If you no longer wish to receive communications from us you may opt-out by calling 877-271-2592 or simply send us an email at privacy@monoprice.com with your email address.
California "Shine The Light"
California residents that have an established business relationship with us can request a list of the personally identifiable information we have shared with third parties for their marketing purposes as well as a list of the third parties that have received such information.
A request can be sent in writing or via email at
privacy@monoprice.com. You can submit a request once each calendar year. Please include an indication that your request is related to a "California Shine the Light" inquiry. Once received, we will respond within a reasonable time.
California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA)
Pursuant to Section 1798.100 et seq. of the California Civil Code, beginning January 1, 2020 residents of California have certain rights with respect to their personal information. California residents may request the categories of personal information we collect for that consumer, categories of sources from which the personal information is collected, the business or commercial purposes for collecting that personal information, the categories of third parties with which we share that personal information, the categories of personal information we share with third parties for a business purpose, and the specific pieces of personal information we have for that consumer. In addition, residents of California may request that we delete any personal information that we may have for that California resident. To submit an access or deletion request, please submit the CCPA Request Form.
Monoprice.com does not discriminate against any consumers because the consumer exercised any of the consumer’s rights under the California Consumer Privacy Act, including, but not limited to, by: (A) denying goods or services to the consumer; (b) charging different prices or rates for goods or services, including through the use of discounts or other benefits or imposing penalties; (c) providing a different level or quality of goods or services to the consumer; or (d) suggesting that the consumer will receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services.
Notification of Changes
If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, our homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our homepage prior to the change becoming effective.
Chat Software
Monoprice utilizes Microsoft’s CRM & CafeX Chat software which facilitates real time customer service interaction. For more information, please refer to
https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement
& https://compliance.cafex.com/en/.
We recommend that you review this policy periodically, as we may update it from time to time.
If you have opted out of receiving communications from Monoprice.com, you will still be able to view news of policy changes at www.monoprice.com. Otherwise, you may e-mail us at support@monoprice.com or call us 877-271-2592 to ask our customer service department about changes and updates.
Our Commitment to Accessibility
Whether you’re using assistive technologies like a screen reader, a magnifier, voice recognition software or switch technology, our mission is to be the destination for Technology at Prices that Make Sense. We set high standards for web accessibility and constantly strive to ensure we’re in compliance with all laws and guidelines. Our team is filled with professionals who are dedicated to making our online experience the best it can be, and we collaborate with advocacy groups, industry partners and vendors to identify areas that need improvement.
If you are visually impaired and are having difficulty navigating this site, please call our Customer Support line via our toll free number 1 (877) 271-2592 for assistance.
Last Update: This is the official Privacy Policy as of Sept 17, 2020
SELF REGULATORY PRIVACY FRAMEWORK
To learn more about our Self Regulatory Privacy Framework, please click on this link:
https://www.monoprice.com/help/SelfRegulatoryPrivacy.
